

IMUENTINYAN NOSARUMEN FRONTEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT INFO

+2349032379922

nosarumenimuentinyan@gmail.co

www.linkedin.com/nosarum en-imuentinyan

Edo State, Nigeria.

EDUCATION

2019-2020

Frontend Web Developer Course freecodecamp.org

2015-2021

Bachelor Degree in Petroleum Engineering

University of Benin

PORTFOLIO

Visti Portfolio Website

ABOUT ME

Proficient Front End Developer effective at developing fast loading and responsive websites that achieve customer and business objectives. Familiar with working alongside a team to determine needs, create plans and optimize design, usability and performance. Well-versed in using Javascript and React as well as other resources to accomplish design requirements.

Prepared to offer my development experience built upon my 2 years of hard work to a growing company while I am also eager to learn and improve on my skills along the way.

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Upwork.com

FREELANCE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

• I improved the performance and design of a clients portfolio website which was bootstrapped with Next.js.

January 2022 - Present

GitHub.com

FRONTEND OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

• I contributed open source projects including an e-commerce project by using React to implement a functioning suggestions search bar to search available items from the API. It enabled users to scale through the items they needed better.

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

BigTunez Entertainment Records

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

• Developed a site for a client who is starting a blog/entertainment news and updates company.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JAVASCRIPT

REACT

TYPESCRIPT

SASS

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES npm, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, SASS, Material UI, Git and Github

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1.) freeCodeCamp.org Responsive Web Design Developer Certification.
- 2.) freeCodeCamp.org JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Developer Certification.

OTHER SKILLS

- extensive knowledge of wordpress CMS.
- proficiency in use of API to request and work with data.
- studying an already existing codebase.
- proficiency in use of API to request and work with data.
- Reading and understanding API documentations.
- Effective communication skills.